edu.pe.ca 2012-10-14

# Government of PEI: Privacy

[ ](http://www.addthis.com/bookmark.php?v=250&username=xa-4bbc898368800927)[](javascript:window.print\(\) "print this page")    

HOME / COPYRIGHT / 

Privacy

 **Privacy Statement**

**Introduction**

The Government of Prince Edward Island takes the privacy of its Internet users seriously. We are committed to protecting the privacy of people whose personal information is held by Government through responsible information management practices.  Any personal information provided to the Government of PEI is collected, used and disclosed in accordance with the _[Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://www.gov.pe.ca/law/statutes/pdf/f-15_01.pdf)_ or other applicable legislation.  This privacy statement explains the website data practices of the Government of PEI.

**What is Personal Information?**

Personal Information is recorded information about an identifiable individual.  Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, date of birth, e-mail address and phone number.  When the Government of PEI collects personal information it must identify:

  * the purpose for collecting the personal information

  * the legal authority for collecting it; and

  * the title, business address and business telephone number of an officer or employee of the Ministry or other government body who can answer questions about the collection of that information.

**What kind of information is being collected?**

If you visit a PEI government website to browse, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit.  The following information is automatically collected and stored:

The Internet Protocol (IP) address and Domain Name used.  The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer.  This address can be translated to determine the Domain Name of your service provider (e.g. gov.pe.ca, xcompany.com); the type of browser and operating system;  
the date and time of the visit; and the web pages or services accessed.

Information collected automatically is used for purpose of assessing system performance, improving web services and web site management.  The Government of PEI does not use this data to determine your identity unless required to do so as part of an internal investigation or other law enforcement purpose.

**Information Collected Directly From You**

Personal information collected, used, disclosed and retained by the PEI Government website is done so under the authority of the _[Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://www.gov.pe.ca/law/statutes/pdf/f-15_01.pdf)_ or other relevant legislation.  Personal information will only be used by authorized staff to fulfill the purpose for which it was originally collected or for a use consistent with that purpose, unless you expressly consent otherwise.  We do not disclose your information to other public bodies or individuals, except as authorized by the [_Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_.](http://www.gov.pe.ca/law/statutes/pdf/f-15_01.pdf)

The PEI Government does not collect personal information unless you voluntarily provide it for the purpose of using specific online services.  However, if you choose not to provide the information required for online services, you may still be able to access government services by traditional methods such as personal contact, fax or mail.  Your decision to not participate in electronic service delivery activities will not impair your ability to browse the web site, read or download any information provided on the site.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended, please direct your inquires to the following contacts.

**What safeguards are in place?**

The Government of PEI is obligated to protect your personal information by making reasonable security arrangements against risks such as unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure or disposal.  Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day operating practices as part of Government's continuing commitment to the protection of personal information.

**How long is information retained?**

The length of retention will vary in relation to the nature of the service.  If the Government of PEI uses your personal information to make a decision that directly affects you, it must retain that information for a least one year so that you have a reasonable opportunity to obtain access to it.  Information collected or created by the Government of PEI is maintained in accordance with Government's records retention schedules and other legislative requirements.

**How can I access and correct information I submit to a website?**

Visitors should be aware that Government of PEI websites may include links to website operated by other government agencies, non-profit organizations and/or private businesses.  When you link to another site, this privacy policy will not apply.  However, you may be subject to the privacy policy of that new site, if one exits.  The Government of PEI is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of external websites.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small file stored on your computer by your web browser when using some Internet sites.  Cookies can also store personal information, such as your name, e-mail address, home or work address, or telephone number.  Persistent cookies can use this type of personal information to identify you whenever you access a website.  Sessional cookies are used to help you move around our website and do not store personal information.  Sessional cookies are valid only during the time you are actually using the website.

The Government of PEI does not use persistent cookies (which may store personal information), but may use sessional cookies (which do not store personal information).

**Changes In Our Privacy Policy**

Any substantive changes to the Government of PEI's privacy policy will be posted on this website.

Who to contact for more information about this privacy policy?

Any questions regarding this privacy policy, or for general information regarding the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act, can be directed to:

Access and Privacy Services  
Department of Finance and Muncipal Affairs  
95 Rochford Street  
2nd Floor, Shaw Building North  
P.O. Box 2000, Charlottetown, PE  
C1A 7N8

Phone:902-569-7542  
Fax:902-368-6164

**If you are not satisfied with our response to your privacy concern, you may wish  
to contact:**

Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner  
J. Angus MacLean Building  
180 Richmond Street  
P.O.Box 2000   
Charlottetown, PE    
C1A 7K7

Phone:902-368-4099  
Fax:902-368-5947
